Guide to the M. L. Rosenthal Papers ca. 1930-1996 MSS 45
New York University Libraries, Publisher
- Series III: Subject Files
  - Subseries B: General
    - Civil liberty (academic liberties debate), undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Classical literature, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Conference materials, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Criticism, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Documents, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Drugs, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Eastern European and Russian literature, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Ecology, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Education, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Education-English Department, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Exams (undergraduate), undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - French literature, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Germany, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Ireland, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Israeli literature, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Juvenilia (1942-43), 1942-1943 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Kavanagh's Weekly, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Latin American and Spanish literature, undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Lectures and articles, undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Lectures and articles, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Lectures and articles, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Lecture notes, exams, syllabi, undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Lectures, talks, broadcasts, readings, undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Linguistics and language, undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Literary history-19th century, undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Literary history-20th century, undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Literary theory, undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Literature and philosophy, religion, myth, undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Literature and politics, undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Literature and psychology, undated (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Literature and science, undated (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Microfilm, etc., undated (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Misc. notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Misc. notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Misc. poems, essays, lectures, etc., undated (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Misc. reviews (mixed) pre-1960 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Misc. reviews (mixed) 1960-64, 1960-1964 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Misc. reviews (mixed) 1965-69, 1965-1969 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Misc. reviews (mixed) 1970-74, 1970-1974 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Notebook of poems (MLR), undated (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Notes on current poetry, undated (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - NYU-English programs, undated (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - NYU-English programs (Sumner, Ives), undated (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Old English, undated (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Oriental literature, undated (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - P.E.N., undated (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Periodicals, undated (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Philosophy, undated (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Pinocchio conference, undated (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Poetry-definitions, attributes, etc., undated (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Poetry-teaching of, undated (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Poetry-tone, voice, readings, etc., undated (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Poets-general, undated (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Pre-modern English language (A - M), undated (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Pre-modern English language (N - Z), undated (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Present Tense, undated (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Publicity (MLR non-book-related), undated (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Radio, undated (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Rockland Country Day School, undated (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Scholarly studies and lectures (Wycherly, Poe, etc.), undated (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - Surrealism-poetry, undated (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - Translation, undated (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - Typography, undated (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - Voice of America, undated (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - War/politics, undated (Box 4, Folder 80)
- Series IV: M.L. Rosenthal's writing
  - Subseries A: book-related
    - Effective Reading (1944) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Exploring Poetry, first edition (1955) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Exploring Poetry (1955) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Exploring Poetry (1955) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Exploring Poetry (1955) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Exploring Poetry (1955) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Exploring Poetry (1955) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Exploring Poetry, second edition (1973) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - A Primer of Ezra Pound, ms. (1960) (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - A Primer of Ezra Pound, reviews and correspondence (1960) (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - The Modern Poets, Chapter 1, ms. (1960) (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - The Modern Poets, Chapter 2, ms. (1960) (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - The Modern Poets, Chapter 3, ms. (1960) (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - The Modern Poets, Chapter 4, ms. (1960) (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - The Modern Poets, reviews and correspondence (1960) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Chief Modern Poets, fourth edition (1962) (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Chief Modern Poets (1962) (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Chief Modern Poets (1962) (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Chief Modern Poets, fourth edition (1962) (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Chief Modern Poets (1962) (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Chief Modern Poets (1962) (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Chief Modern Poets (1962) (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Chief Modern Poets (1962) (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Chief Modern Poets (1962) (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Chief Modern Poets, fifth edition (1970) (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Chief Modern Poets, sixth edition, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Selected Poems and... of William Butler Yeats (1962) (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Blue Boy on Skates, ms. (1964) (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Blue Boy on Skates, ms. (1964) (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Blue Boy on Skates (1964) (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Blue Boy on Skates (1964) (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - The William Carlos Williams Reader (1966) (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - The New Poets, ms. (1967) (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - The New Poets, ms. (1967) (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - The New Poets, ms. (1967) (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - The New Poets, ms. (1967) (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - The New Modern Poetry (1967) (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - The New Modern Poetry, permissions and correspondence (1967) (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - The New Modern Poetry, permissions/paperback (1969) (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - 100 Postwar Poems (1968) (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - 100 Postwar Poems (1968) (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Beyond Power, ms. (1969) (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Beyond Power, ms. (1969) (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Beyond Power (1969) (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Beyond Power, review, correspondence, etc. (1969) (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Randall Jarrell (1972) (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - The View from the Peacock's Tail, ms. (1972) (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - The View from the Peacock's Tail (1972) (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - The View from the Peacock's Tail (1972) (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - The View from the Peacock's Tail, reviews, etc. (1972) (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Poetry and the Common Life, correspondence and permissions (1974) (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Poetry and the Common Life, reviews and publicity (1974) (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - She, ms. (1977) (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - She (1977) (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - She, reviews and publicity (1977) (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Sailing Into the Unknown (1978) (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Sailing Into the Unknown, correspondence, reviews, publicity, etc. (1978) (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Poems 1964-1980, Oxford UP publicity and correspondence (1981), 1964-1980, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Poems 1964-1980, reviews and publicity (1981), 1964-1980, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - The Adventures of Pinocchio (1983) (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - The Adventures of Pinocchio, correspondence (1983) (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - The Adventures of Pinocchio, reviews and publicity (1983) (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Pinocchio (1983) (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Pinocchio (1983) (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Pinocchio (1983) (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Pinocchio (1983) (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Pinocchio (1983) (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Pinocchio (1983) (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - The Modern Poetic Sequence (1983) (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - The Modern Poetic Sequence, correspondence (1983) (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - The Modern Poetic Sequence, reviews and publicity (1983) (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - The Modern Poetic Sequence, ms. (1983) (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - The Modern Poetic Sequence, ms. (1983) (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - The Modern Poetic Sequence, ms. (1983) (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - The Modern Poetic Sequence, ms. (1983) (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - The Modern Poetic Sequence, galley (1983) (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - The Modern Poetic Sequence, galley (1983) (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - The Modern Poetic Sequence, proofs (1983) (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - The Modern Poetic Sequence, proofs (1983) (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - The Modern Poetic Sequence, proofs (1983) (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - The Modern Poetic Sequence, paperback (1985) (Box 5, Folder 81)
    - The Poet's Art, ms. (1987) (Box 5, Folder 82)
    - The Poet's Art, ms. (1987) (Box 5, Folder 83)
    - The Poet's Art, correspondence, reviews, publicity (1987) (Box 5, Folder 84)
    - Poetry In English, introduction (1987) (Box 5, Folder 85)
    - Poetry In English, correspondence, etc. (1987) (Box 5, Folder 86)
    - As for Love, drafts (1987) (Box 5, Folder 87)
    - As for Love, reviews and publicity (1987) (Box 5, Folder 88)
    - Our Life in Poetry (1991) (Box 5, Folder 89)
    - Our Life in Poetry, correspondence, reviews, publicity (1991) (Box 5, Folder 90)
    - "Works-In-Progress" Ploughshares 17 (MLR guest editor), correspondence (1991) (Box 6, Folder 91)
    - "Works-In-Progress" Ploughshares 17, correspondence, reviews, publicity (1991) (Box 6, Folder 92)
    - Running to Paradise (1994) (Box 6, Folder 93)
    - Running to Paradise, reviews and publicity (1994) (Box 6, Folder 94)
    - In the World Pub, ms. (1995-96), 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 95)
    - In the World Pub (1995-96), 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 96)
    - In the World Pub (1995-96), 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 97)
    - In the World Pub, drafts of sequence (1995-96), 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 98)
    - In the World Pub (1995-96), 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 99)
    - In the World Pub (1995-96), 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 100)
    - In the World Pub (1995-96), 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 101)
    - In the World Pub (1995-96), 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 102)
    - In the World Pub, drafts of poems not used? (1995-96), ?1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 103)
    - In the World Pub, drafts of recent poems (1995-96), 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 104)
    - Misc. book-related, undated (Box 6, Folder 105)
    - Notes towards book for Oxford (not written), undated (Box 6, Folder 106)
    - Notes and correspondence towards revised edition of Chief Modern Poets (not published), undated (Box 6, Folder 107)
    - Possible book project, undated (Box 6, Folder 108)
  - Subseries B: essays, poems, reviews, lectures
    - Classroom notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Classroom notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence re: essays, introductions, forewords, etc., undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Dissertation: "Chief Poets of the American Depression", undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Dissertation, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Dissertation, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Dissertation, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Dissertation, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Editorship-Macmillan, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Editorship-Maximum Security Ward, reviews and correspondence, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Editorship-The Nation, correspondence, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Editorship-Present Tense, correspondence, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Engagements, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Essays (A), undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Essays (B-D), undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Essays (E-I), undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Essays (L-M), undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Essays (N), undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Essays (O), undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Essays (P), undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Essays (Q-S), undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Essays (T-Z), undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Essays (pre-1950) (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Essays (1950-1959) (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Essays (1960-1969) (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Essays (1970-1979) (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Essays in progress, undated (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Forewords, undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Interviews, undated (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Introductions, undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Introductions (reviews and correspondence), undated (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Lectures / Readings, undated (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Lectures / Readings, undated (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Lectures / Readings, undated (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Lectures / Readings, undated (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Lectures / Readings, undated (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Misc. poems, undated (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Misc. poems, undated (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Misc. poems, undated (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Misc. poems, undated (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - Misc. poems, undated (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - Misc. poems (published versions), undated (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - Misc. short papers, abstracts, fragments, etc., undated (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - Notes for reviews, articles, books, talks, undated (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - Reviews (A-G), undated (Box 9, Folder 45)
    - Reviews (H-N), undated (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - Reviews (O-P), undated (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - Reviews (R-Z), undated (Box 9, Folder 48)
    - Reviews (pre-1950) (Box 9, Folder 49)
    - Reviews (1950-1959) (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - Reviews (1960-1969) (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - Reviews (1970-1979) (Box 9, Folder 52)
- Series V: Printed Material
  - Subseries A: Rosenthal's publications
    - The 'Actaeon-Principle' in The Southern Review, Summer 1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Aerian, pretentios... [Romanian] in Steaua, July 1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Alice, Huck,... and "1991-1992 (in memoriam DHR)" in Southern Review, Summer 1993, 1991-1992, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Alienation of Sensibility and 'Modernity' in Approaches to the..., May 17-18, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Alienation of Sensibility and 'Modernity' in The Poetry Review, Winter 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - American Elegy in Pequod, no. 35, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - The Aroused Language of Modern... in NYT Magazine, Nov. 24, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - At the Last in Poetry, Oct.-Nov. 1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Awake and Remember! in Southern Review, Summer 1992 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Bill Arrowsmith-'Noble Acerbity' in Arion, Spring/Fall 1992-93, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - A Contemporary Aesthetic Injustice in College English, May 1942 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - The Corruption of Aschenbach in U of Kansas City Review, Autumn 1947 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Criticism: Starting from Scratch in The Missouri Review, Spring 1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Cultural and Rhetorical Symbols... in Symbols and Values, 13th symposium (1954) (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Discovering E. P. In Paideuma, Fall/Winter 1986 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Early Yeats: Poems Before 1900... in Yeats Eliot Review, Winter 1994, 1900-1994 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - e. e. c. (elan et courage) in Spring, Fall 1994 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Elegy 1991-1992 in Exile, vol. 17, no. 3 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Entretien avec M. L. Rosenthal [French] in La Quinzaine litteraire, 15 Oct. 1971 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Footnote in QRL, vol. 9, no.4, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Hardy's Satires: Hard Knowledge... in Southern Review, Summer 1991 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Hemingway's Achievement in Pleasures in Learning, Dec. 1961 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - His Eye Is On the Critic in Audience, Summer 1959 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - His Present Discontents in Shenandoah, Fall 1971 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Horace Gregory's Catullus Translations in Accen t, Spring 1950 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - The Humanities-Our Secret Crisis in The Humanist, May/June 1977 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Hurrah for Longinus!... in Southern Review, Winter 1989 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - In the World Pub in Exile, vol. 19, no. 3, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Intermission in AntFus, Autumn 1972 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Like a Man With a Bullet Wound in Review 72, Fall 1972 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Like Morning Light in Salmagundi, Spring 1972 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - 'A Midrash of Hieroglyph': Ben Belitt's 'Sumac' in Salmagundi, Summer 1990 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Modern Irish Poetry in Southern Review, Summer 1995 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Modern Poetry in... a scrawny cry, Spring 1964 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - 'Modernity' and the New Poetry from The New Poets, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - A Modest Anthology in Review 75, Fall 1975 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Notes on Some Afro-Cuban Translations in Phylon, vol. 6, no.3 (1945) (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Notes Toward an Unauthorized Autobiography in Pequod, no. 23/24, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Nya Songer Och Ny Song [Swedish] in BLM, Sept. 1963 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - October Again, "Wedding.. ." and "A Place in Time" in Southern Review, Summer 1990 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Olson/His Poetry in Massachusetts Review, Winter 1971 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - On Being a Jewish Poet in Present Tense, Winter 1976 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - On the 'Dissidents' of the Thirties in U of Kansas City Review, Summer 1951 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - On Yeats and the Cultural Symbolism... in Yale Review, Summer 1960 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Pinocchio (translated by MLR) in Cricket, Nov. 1993 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Plastic Possibilities in Poetry, Nov. 1971 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - poems from Beyond Power in Stations, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - from Poems 1966-1980 [Chinese] in Foreign Poetry, no.4 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Poetic 'Experiment' in Spring, Fall 1995 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Poetic Power-Free the Swan! in Shenandoah, Fall 1972 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Poetry Pilot (guest editor, MLR) April 1987 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Primo Levi (translated my MLR) in Exile, vol. 18, no.2, undated (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Problems of Robert Creeley in Parnassus, Fall/Winter 1973 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - The 'Pure' Poetry of Horace Gregory in Modern Poetry Studies, Spring 1973 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Reality... and "Farewell" in Poetry, Dec. 1967 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - review of Dance of the Intellect in Modern Philology, August 1988 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - review of Pablo Neruda and Cesar Vallejo in Review '68, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Shadow-Runners in Southern Review, Spring 1995 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Snow Man in Ploughshares, Fall 1991 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Steven's Sea Surface Full of Clouds in The Explicator, Mar. 1961 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - A Toast to Hugh Kenner in William Carlos Williams Review, Spring/Fall 1993 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Through Streets Where smiling Children in MPS, Autumn 1977 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Two Poems in Northwest, Autumn 1962 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Uncertain Odysseus in Shenendoah, Winter 1968 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Visiting Yeats's Tower and "Geometries of Haifa" in QRL, vol.17, no. 1-2, undated (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Voyage in Neruda in Review 74, Spring 1974 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - The Waste Land as on Open Structure in Mosaic, vol.6, no.1, undated (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - from "The World Pub," Led by the Love.. ." and "Intro." in Ploughshares, Spring 1991 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Subseries B: miscellaneous
    - Misc. journals, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Misc. journals, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Offprints/reprints, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Offprints/reprints, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Offprints/reprints, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Offprints/reprints, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Offprints/reprints, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Offprints/reprints, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Offprints/reprints, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Offprints/reprints, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Offprints/reprints, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Printed material, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Printed material, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Printed material, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Printed material (see oversize box), undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous printed material (no folders), undated (Box 4)
- Series VI: Biographical material
  - Biographical, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biographical, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Biographical, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Biographical, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Biographical/Juvenilia (see oversize box), undated (Box 1, Folder 4b.)
  - China, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Confessions, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Juvenilia, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Juvenilia, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Juvenilia, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Juvenilia, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Juvenilia-correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Memorial for MLR, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - MLR's bibliography (original handwritten and typed sectioned), undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Writings about MLR, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Writing about MLR: reactions to NYT piece, etc., undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - American Literary Scholarship, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Bibliographical material, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Book-related (early stages), undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Book-related (early stages), undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Book-related (notes), undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Book-related (notes), undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs-Division for Americans Abroad, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - China, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - College thesis, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Conference of science, philosophy and religion, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Contracts, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Course-related, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Course-related, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Courses and notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Courses and notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Coursework notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Delmore Schwartz Award, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Delmore Schwartz Award, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - English 282: Background of English Restoration Theatre, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - English G41.3926: Readings in Modern Poetry, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - English G41.3927: Modern Irish Poetry, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - English G41.3954: Poetic Criticism, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - English V41.0600, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Exams, undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - The Humanist, undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Journals, undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Mss, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Mss, undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Mss, undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Mss, undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Mss, undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Misc., undated (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Misc., undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Misc., undated (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Misc., undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Misc., undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Misc., undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Misc. notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Misc. notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - MSU: Eng 7028400-Literary Concepts, undated (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - NEH Summer Institute, undated (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - NEH Summer Institute, undated (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Notebooks, undated (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Notebooks, undated (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Notebooks, undated (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Notebooks, undated (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Notebooks, undated (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Notebooks, undated (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Notebooks, undated (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Notebooks, undated (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Notebooks, undated (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Notebooks, undated (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Notebooks, undated (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Notebooks, undated (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Notebooks, undated (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Notebooks, undated (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Notebooks, undated (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Notes-Eliot, undated (Box 5, Folder 74)